A Guide to the Papers of Louisa May Alcott 1848 (1863-1888) 1956
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Louisa May Alcott 1848 (1863-1888) 1956
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
6255 through 6255-k
312 items (3 boxes).
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The Papers of Louisa May Alcott were deposited in the Library at various dates (see following) by Clifton Waller Barrett. The deposits were made gifts on July 1, 1991. 6255-k, a photograph, was purchased from E. Wharton and Co. on September 3, 2003.
6255: deposit, March 19, 1960; gift July 1, 1991
6255-a: deposit, October 18, 1963; gift July 1, 1991
6255-b: deposit, December 17, 1964; gift July 1, 1991
6255-c: deposit, March 3, 1964; gift July 1, 1991
6255-d: deposit, April 7, 1965; gift July 1, 1991
6255-e: deposit, October 21, 1965; gift July 1, 1991
6255-f: deposit, October 21, 1965; gift July 1, 1991
6255-g: deposit, October 21, 1965; gift July 1, 1991
6255-h: deposit, December 30, 1966; gift July 1, 1991
6255-i: deposit, February 13, 1968; gift July 1, 1991
6255-j: deposit, March 13, 1970; gift July 1, 1991
6255-k: purchase, September 3, 2003
Biographical/Historical Information
Nineteenth-century American writer Louisa May Alcott was the author of the acclaimed and beloved children's classic Little Women and numerous other popular works for children. Though she produced adult novels and stories as well, Alcott is most celebrated for her children's fiction, which includes the eight novels grouped under the "Little Women" series. Autobiographical in nature, Alcott's "Little Women" books were modeled after her parents and sisters as well as friends and neighbors in her native New England, and she is credited with being a pioneer in the creation of realistic fiction for children. Her novels are noted for their perceptive and highly entertaining accounts of childhood, for her portrayal of children as multi-dimensional, thinking individuals, and for her lively and warm depictions of family life. Alcott enjoyed widespread popularity in her lifetime as a children's author, while today books like Little Women and Little Men--which have been translated into numerous foreign languages--are still read and appreciated by children around the world.
Alcott was born on November 29, 1832, in Germantown, Pennsylvania, the second of four daughters of Amos Bronson Alcott, a noted transcendentalist philosopher and educator, and Abigail May, a descendant of one of Boston's more prominent families. Money was scarce in the Alcott family; the eccentric Amos Alcott's various social and educational experiments, and his inability to maintain a stable income, often brought the family to the brink of poverty. One particularly grand failure--a utopian community called Fruitlands established by Amos in Harvard, Massachusetts--was a turning point for the young Louisa. From the young age of twelve, she decided to become responsible as a provider for her family, a resolve which lasted her whole life.
Alcott was predominantly raised in Concord, Massachusetts, just outside of Boston. While money was scarce during Louisa's upbringing, intellectual and family life were exceptionally rich. Never formally educated, Louisa and her sisters were taught at home by their father, who brought them into contact with some of the great intellectuals of the day, including Ralph Waldo Emerson, Nathaniel Hawthorne, Henry David Thoreau, and Margaret Fuller. Louisa, who tutored Emerson's daughter Ellen, spent many hours in Emerson's library, where she read classics of both philosophy and literature. Alcott was very appreciative of the unconventional teaching methods pursued by her father. "Very happy hours they were to us, for my father taught in the wise way which unfolds what lies in the child's nature, as a flower blooms, rather than crammed it, like a Strasburg goose, with more than it could digest," she wrote in her journal collected in Louisa May Alcott: Her Life, Letters and Journals. The Alcotts were a progressively minded family, and Louisa, like the rest of her family, was a supporter of a number of reform causes, including women's suffragmente, coeducation, and the abolition of slavery.
Domestic life in the Alcott household was one marked by hard work, a teaching of skills such as sewing and clothes-making, and an encouragement of playtime and independent thinking. Alcott's beloved mother was her closest friend and confidant, who encouraged the precocious and headstrong Louisa to lead a life of independence and high values. Each of the Alcott girls was required to keep journals which their parents regularly read, and Louisa particularly valued her mother's comments.
Around the age of sixteen, Alcott moved with her family to Boston, and the city-life was stressful for a girl accustomed to living and playing in the hills and countryside. Although financial burdens continued to fall upon Louisa, her sisters, and her mother, charity and volunteer work were always priorities for the family. In 1850, Louisa began work as a teacher after her sister Anna married, and around this time she also began working very hard at becoming a writer. Louisa found she could readily make money by turning out sentimental and thriller stories for adult magazines, and she became a regular contributor to a number of periodicals, often writing "blood and thunder" stories of passion and revenge under the pseudonym of A. M. Barnard. Louisa longed to do something more serious, however, and began working on two novels for adults. Although she had no particular intent to become a children's writer, her first book, Flower Fables, published when she was twenty-three, was a collection of fairy stories she had originally written while she was a tutor for Emerson's daughter, Ellen.
In 1858, Alcott's sister Elizabeth died after a long illness during which Louisa had provided much care. When the Civil War broke out three years later, Alcott worked at a Union hospital in the District of Columbia. Alcott's letters to her family recounting her nursing experiences were published in 1863 as Hospital Sketches, and earned Alcott a fair amount of critical and commercial success. After only a month at the hospital, however, she contracted typhoid fever, which committed her to long periods of bed rest, and which would impair her health for the rest of her life.
Still wanting more new experiences, and frustrated by the unfavorable reception of her next work, an adult novel entitled Moods published in 1865, Alcott travelled to Europe as the companion of an invalid friend. When she returned in July of 1866, she soon began work on more magazine stories. In 1867, she became editor of a children's monthly magazine, Merry's Museum, the same year that Thomas Niles, an editor at Alcott's publisher Roberts Brothers, approached her with the prospect of writing a girls' book. Although she was hesitant, Alcott began working in May of the following year on what would become Little Women, drawing upon the real-life characters and experiences of her parents and three sisters, Anna, Elizabeth, and May.
Written in six weeks in 1868, Little Women, however, proved Alcott tremendously wrong. The book was an instant sensation as readers relished the autobiographical characters of Jo, Meg, Amy, and Beth, and their parents Mr. and Mrs. March. A second volume was quickly planned and written in two months, and in 1869 was published as Little Women or, Meg, Jo, Beth and Amy, Part Second. Both critically and commercially successful, Little Women follows the four March sisters as they strive to improve upon their characters and become "good girls." The novel made giant strides in providing realistic fiction for children, and also in providing a new scope for the traditional "family" novel.
Critics consider Little Women Alcott's masterpiece, yet she followed its success with numerous stories and novels that continued to very popular among her reading fans. Seven of these novels are often grouped with Little Women under the "Little Women" series: An Old-Fashioned Girl, Little Men, Eight Cousins, Rose in Bloom, Under the Lilacs, Jack and Jill, and Jo's Boys and How they Turned Out. These novels follow the lives of the March sisters and their families as they grow older, in addition to the relatives and residents of the New England towns where they lived. The novels demonstrate many of Alcott's beliefs, including the shallowness of materialism, a belief in coeducation and other educational reforms held by her father, and a feminism which supported the idea of self-dependence for women and criticized many of the social customs expected of them.
Alcott was also a prolific author of short stories for children, many which were collected in a series of books entitled Aunt Jo's Scrap-Bag. Her success as a writer brought her much fame and financial security in her lifetime, and she continued to provide for her mother and father, as well as other members of her family. She served as legal guardian of her sister May's daughter Louisa, and later also adopted her sister Anna's son, John Sewell Pratt. Alcott herself was never married, once remarking that writing seemed to be her intended companion for life. Alcott died on March 6, 1888, two days after her father's death. While she was the most successful and prolific children's author of her day, Alcott continues to be most noted for her achievement in Little Women.
Scope and Content
The Papers of Louisa May Alcott consists of literary manuscripts, correspondence, legal documents, photographs, and other miscellaneous items. Correspondence discusses her literary career, the writing and publication of her novels and short stories, her family, friends, financial affairs, her health and physicians, and her social life. In addition, there are references to the Concord School of Philosophy, and the career of artist Abigail May Alcott.
Correspondents include: Abigail May Alcott, Amos Bronson Alcott, John Sewall Pratt Alcott, Ariadne Blish, Lydia Maria Francis Child, William Warland Clapp, Mary Mapes Dodge, J.R. Elliott, ed. of Flag of our union; Daniel Sharp Ford, Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, Horace B. Fuller, Laura Hosmer, A.K. Loring, Thomas Niles, William J. Niles, J.R. Osgood, Lydia Dodge Cabot Parker, Elizabeth Palmer Peabody, Anna Alcott Pratt, James Redpath, Sampson Low, Son & Marston, London; Scribner & Company, New York; Tauchitz, publishers, Leipzig; Howard Malcom Ticknor, William Hayes Ward.
There is also correspondence and documents regarding the will and estate of Miss Alcott; and correspondence between John S.P. Alcott and Jessie Bonstelle Stuart regarding the dramatization of Little Women. There are complete manuscripts for many of her short stories; and pages from the following: An Old Fashioned Girl, Daisy's Ball, Jack and Jill, Jo's Boys, and The Pickwick. Printed material includes obituaries of Miss Alcott, and reviews of her works. There are also photographs, a silhouette, and a portrait of Miss Alcott.
Contents List
- Series I: Papers, correspondence, and printed matter regarding the will and estate of Louisa May Alcott and dramatization rights to Little Women
  - "Memorandum of agreement..." 1875 May 31, TD copy 1 p. (Box-folder 1:1)
    regarding copyrights of Louisa May Alcott. 6255
  - Last will and testament of Louisa May Alcott 1887 July 10, TD copy 3 p. (Box-folder 1:2)
    6255
  - Last will and testament of Louisa May Alcott 1887 July 10, TD copy 4 p. (Box-folder 1:3)
  - Deed for sale of Alcott property 1899 October 12, DS 4 p. (Box-folder 1:4)
  - Trust bond to John S.P. Alcott 1910 April 1, DS 4 p. (Box-folder 1:5)
  - Henry Wheeler to Paul R. Blackmur 1910 May 19, TLS 1 p. (Box-folder 1:6)
    regarding trust. 6255
  - Walter C. Wright to John S.P. Alcott 1910 July 13, TL carbon 1 p. (Box-folder 1:7)
  - Agreement re: rights to dramatization of Little Women 1910 July 25, TD 1 p. (Box-folder 1:8)
  - [lawyer] to John S.P. Alcott 1910 July 27, TL carbon 2 p. (Box-folder 1:9)
    re: trust. 6255
  - Jessie Bonstelle [Stuart] to John [S.P.] Alcott 1910 August 12, TLS 1 p. (Box-folder 1:10)
    regarding dramatization rights. 6255
  - [John Alcott] to Mrs. Jessie Bonstelle 1910 August 18, TL carbon 1 p. (Box-folder 1:11)
  - [John Alcott] to Henry Wheeler 1910 August 18, TL carbon 2 p. (Box-folder 1:12)
    regarding Louisa May Alcott estate. 6255
  - Jessie Bonstelle to John Alcott 1910 August 27, TLS with envelope 1 p. (Box-folder 1:13)
  - [John Alcott] to Mrs. Jessie Bonstelle 1910 August 29, TL carbon 1 p. (Box-folder 1:14)
  - [John Alcott] to Jessie Bonstelle 1910 September 1, TL carbon 1 p. (Box-folder 1:15)
  - Jessie Bonstelle Stuart to John Alcott 1910 September 8, TLS 1 p. (Box-folder 1:16)
  - Agreement re: dramatization of Little Women 1910 September 10, TDS 2 p. (Box-folder 1:17)
  - [John Alcott] to Mrs. Jessie B. Stuart 1910 September 12, TL carbon 1 p. (Box-folder 1:18)
  - Robert Melville Baker to John P. Alcott 1910 September 13, TLS with envelope 1 p. (Box-folder 1:19)
  - Agreement regarding dramatization of Little Women 1910 September 20, TD carbon 3 p. (Box-folder 1:20)
  - John Alcott to Mrs. Jessie B. Stuart 1910 September 26, TL copy 1 p. (Box-folder 1:21)
  - Settlement between J.S.P. Alcott and Louisa May Rasim in regarding estate "questions and controversies" [1910 October 12], TD draft 7 p. (Box-folder 1:22)
  - Settlement between J.S.P. Alcott and Louisa May Rasim in regarding estate "questions and controversies" [1910 October 12], TD carbon 7 p. (Box-folder 1:23)
  - Probate court papers regarding final settlement of Alcott will 1910 October 12-17, TDs carbon 29 p. (Box-folder 1:24)
    p. 1-4 petition of J.S.P. Alcott & Cate VS Louisa May Rasim
    p. 5-12 settlement of J.S.P Alcott etal and Louisa May Rasim
    p. 13 Emil F. Rasim power of attorney to join settlement
    p. 14 James M. Newell as guardian for Pratt children
    p. 15-17 decree of Probate Court of Middlesex County, MA
    p. 18 Louisa May Rasim receipt of proceeds from estate
    p. 19 John S.P. Alcott receipt of proceeds from estate
    p. 20 Jessica L. Pratt receipt of proceeds from estate
    p. 21 [Louisa M.] Rasim receipt of proceeds from outside
    p. 22-27 [James M. Newell] report as Guardian ad litem
    p. 28-29 agreement to apportion probate taxes
  - [lawyer's] list of activities, 1910 March 28-October 17, regarding controversy over will of Louisa May Alcott 1910 October 15, TD 7 p. (Box-folder 1:25)
  - Notes and documents regarding Louisa May Alcott estate [1910], AD/TD 24 p. (Box-folder 1:26)
    p. 1 copy of Louisa May Alcott instructions to "My Dearest Boys"
    p. 2-3 copy of Louisa May Alcott instructions "My Wishes"
    p. 4 [Louisa May Alcott estate income], 1905-1909, "J.S.P. Alcott, Trustee"
    p. 5-6 [J.S.P. Alcott] draft letter re: appointing new trustee
    p. 7-8 [J.S.P. Alcott] notes "Memo in Louisa May Alcott Estate"
    p. 9-10 [J.S.P. Alcott] "Memoranda in the Alcott Trust Matter"
    p. 11-14 inventory of Louisa May Alcott estate (original and attorney's copy)
    p. 15-24 [Louisa May Alcott] "Trust Estate Inventories," distribution [proposals], and interest income projections
- Series II: Correspondence
  - Abigail May Alcott to Louisa May Alcott 1856 January 8, ALS 4 p. (Box-folder 1:27)
    6255-b
  - Louisa May Alcott to [Abigail May Alcott] verso ca. 1864, AL fragment 1 p. (Box-folder 1:28)
    clippings regarding Moods, etc. 6255-b
  - Abigail May Alcott to Louisa May Alcott 1865 November 29, AL fragment 2 p. (Box-folder 1:29)
  - Abigail May Alcott to Louisa May Alcott n.y. November 29, ALS 2 p. (Box-folder 1:30)
  - Abigail May Alcott to Louisa May Alcott n.d., ALS 2 p. (Box-folder 1:31)
  - Abigail May Alcott to Louisa May Alcott n.d., AL fragment 2 p. (Box-folder 1:32)
  - A. Bronson Alcott to Louisa May Alcott 1868 February 19, ALS 4 p. (Box-folder 1:33)
  - Louisa May Alcott to A. Bronson Alcott 1872 November 29, ALS 4 p. (Box-folder 1:34)
  - Louisa May Alcott to A. Bronson Alcott [1872] December 8, AL 6 p. (Box-folder 1:35)
  - Louisa May Alcott to A. Bronson Alcott 1875 January 3, AL fragment 2 p. (Box-folder 1:36)
  - Louisa May Alcott to A. Bronson Alcott n.y. December 12-13, ALS 8 p. (Box-folder 1:37)
  - Louisa May Alcott to John S. Pratt [Alcott] [1887 July 28], ALS with address 2 p. (Box-folder 1:38)
  - Louisa May Alcott to John S. Pratt [Alcott] [1888 January 18], ALS with envelope 2 p. (Box-folder 1:39)
  - Louisa May Alcott to [John S. Pratt Alcott] n.y. January 3, ALS 2 p. (Box-folder 1:40)
  - Louisa May Alcott to [John S. Pratt Alcott] n.y. January 30, ALS 2 p. (Box-folder 1:41)
  - Louisa May Alcott to John [S. Pratt Alcott] "Monday", ALS 2 p. (Box-folder 1:42)
  - Louisa May Alcott to [John S. Pratt Alcott] n.d., ALS 4 p. (Box-folder 1:43)
  - Louisa May Alcott to John S. Pratt [Alcott] n.d., ALS with address 1 p. (Box-folder 1:44)
  - Louisa May Alcott to [John S. Pratt Alcott] "Thursday", ALS 2 p. (Box-folder 1:45)
  - Louisa May Alcott to [John S. Pratt Alcott] n.d., ALS 2 p. (Box-folder 1:46)
  - Louisa May Alcott to [John S. Pratt Alcott] n.d., ALS 2 p. (Box-folder 1:47)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Mr. Allen n.d., ALS 2 p. (Box-folder 1:48)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Mrs. Atkinson [1886] February 10, ALS 2 p. (Box-folder 1:49)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Mrs. Atkinson [1886] February 17, ALS 3 p. (Box-folder 1:50)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Geo[rge] A. Bacon n.y. April, env 1 p. (Box-folder 1:51)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Miss Baker n.y. April 2, ALS 2 p. (Box-folder 1:52)
    6255-e
  - Louisa May Alcott to Ariadne Blish [1875] October 9, ALS with envelope 3 p. (Box-folder 1:53)
  - Ariadne Blish to Louisa May Alcott 1875 October 14, ALS 2 p. (Box-folder 1:54)
  - Marion Stevens to Arnold Silverman, regarding preceding letter 1956 May 20, 1 p. (Box-folder 1:54)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Mrs. F. Brown n.d., ALS with address 2 p. (Box-folder 1:55)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Louisa Canfield n.y. November 22, APCS 1 p. (Box-folder 1:56)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Mr. Chandler n.y. June 27, ALS 3 p. (Box-folder 1:57)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Mr. Chase with transcript n.y. February 17, ALS 4 p. (Box-folder 1:58)
    6255-g
  - L. Maria Child to Louisa May Alcott 1878 June 19, ALS 4 p. (Box-folder 1:59)
  - W.W. Clapp, Jr. to Louisa May Alcott 1865 January 7, ALS 3 p. (Box-folder 1:60)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Miss Clark n.y. July 15, ALS 3 p. (Box-folder 1:61)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Mrs. Clement n.y. September 6, ALS 4 p. (Box-folder 1:62)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Mrs. Coale n.y. November 1, ALS 1 p. (Box-folder 1:63)
    6255-h
  - Louisa May Alcott to L. Clark Davis (photocopy) n.y. June 4, ALS with envelope 4 p. (Box-folder 1:64)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Mr. Denny with transcript [1868] December 14, ALS with envelope 3 p. (Box-folder 1:65)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Mrs. Devens [1879] November 15, ALS with envelope 4 p. (Box-folder 1:66)
  - Mary Mapes Dodge to Louisa May Alcott 1880 January 22, ALS 4 p. (Box-folder 1:67)
  - Mary Mapes Dodge to Louisa May Alcott 1882 March 15, ALS 6 p. (Box-folder 1:68)
  - Mary Mapes Dodge to Louisa May Alcott 1882 October 18, ALS 2 p. (Box-folder 1:69)
  - Mary Mapes Dodge to Louisa May Alcott 1884 January 12, ALS 2 p. (Box-folder 1:70)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Mary Mapes Dodge n.y. May 1, APCS 1 p. (Box-folder 1:71)
  - Mary Mapes Dodge to Louisa May Alcott n.y. July 24, ALS 4 p. (Box-folder 1:72)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Mary Mapes Dodge n.y. August 17, AL fragment 4 p. (Box-folder 1:73)
  - J.R. Elliott to Louisa May Alcott 1865 March 25, ALS 2 p. (Box-folder 1:74)
  - J.R. Elliott to Louisa May Alcott 1866 August 14, ALS 2 p. (Box-folder 1:75)
  - J.R. Elliott to Louisa May Alcott 1866 December 4, ALS 2 p. (Box-folder 1:76)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Mr. Farmer 1872 June 17, ALS 3 p. (Box-folder 1:77)
  - Dan[iel] L. Ford to Louisa May Alcott 1872 December 28, ALS 3 p. (Box-folder 1:78)
  - Dan[iel] L. Ford to Louisa May Alcott 1873 April 30, ALS 3 p. (Box-folder 1:79)
  - Dan[iel] L. Ford to Louisa May Alcott 1873 August 14, ALS 4 p. (Box-folder 1:80)
  - [Daniel L. Ford] to Louisa May Alcott 1875 January 29, AL fragment 4 p. (Box-folder 1:81)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Miss [Ford] n.d., ALS 3 p. (Box-folder 1:82)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Miss F n.d., ALS 1 p. (Box-folder 1:83)
  - Horace B. Fuller account with Louisa May Alcott verso: Louisa May Alcott note 1868 July 13, ADS 1 p. (Box-folder 1:84)
  - Horace B. Fuller to Louisa May Alcott 1869 June 16, ALS 4 p. (Box-folder 1:85)
  - Horace B. Fuller to Louisa May Alcott 1869 September 6, ALS 2 p. (Box-folder 1:86)
  - Horace B. Fuller to Louisa May Alcott 1871 October 24, ALS 2 p. (Box-folder 1:87)
  - Horace B. Fuller to [Louisa May Alcott] n.d., ALS 1 p. (Box-folder 1:88)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Mr. Gluck n.y. December 2, ALS 2 p. (Box-folder 1:89)
  - Maria Goodapple to Louisa May Alcott 1883 September 26, ALS 3 p. (Box-folder 1:90)
  - Louisa May Alcott to [Elizabeth B. Greene] with transcript [1869] April 1, ALS 4 p. (Box-folder 1:91)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Miss Halley n.y. December 8, ALS 4 p. (Box-folder 1:92)
  - [J.A. Nauschek] to Marsha Heath n.y. November 10, Card with envelope 1 p. (Box-folder 1:93)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Abby Hosmer n.y. May 25, APCS 1 p. (Box-folder 1:94)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Laura Hosmer [1881 January 12], ALS with envelope 1 p. (Box-folder 1:95)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Laura Hosmer [1881 March 3], ALS with envelope 4 p. (Box-folder 1:96)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Laura Hosmer [1882 December 23], Card with envelope 1 p. (Box-folder 1:97)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Laura Hosmer [1884 February 18], ALS with envelope 2 p. (Box-folder 1:98)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Laura Hosmer [1884 March 27], ALS with envelope 4 p. (Box-folder 1:99)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Laura Hosmer [1885 March 16], ALS with envelope 4 p. (Box-folder 1:100)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Laura Hosmer [1885] August 19, ALS with envelope 3 p. (Box-folder 1:101)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Laura Hosmer [1885 September 2], ALS with envelope 1 p. (Box-folder 1:102)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Laura Hosmer [1885] November 29, ALS with envelope 4 p. (Box-folder 1:103)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Laura Hosmer [1886 January 29], ALS with envelope 4 p. (Box-folder 1:104)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Laura Hosmer [1886] February 13, ALS with envelope 1 p. (Box-folder 1:105)
    with memo regarding date. 6255-b
  - Louisa May Alcott to Laura Hosmer [1886 May 2], ALS with envelope 2 p. (Box-folder 1:106)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Laura Hosmer [1886 May 14], ALS with envelope 4 p. (Box-folder 1:107)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Laura Hosmer [1886 May 19], ALS with envelope 4 p. (Box-folder 1:108)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Laura Hosmer [1886 May 25], AL with envelope 2 p. (Box-folder 1:109)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Laura Hosmer [1886] November 30, ALS with envelope 4 p. (Box-folder 1:110)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Laura Hosmer [1887] February 3, ALS with envelope 3 p. (Box-folder 1:111)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Laura Hosmer [1887] March 6, ALS with envelope 4 p. (Box-folder 1:112)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Laura Hosmer 1887 June 1, ALS with envelope 2 p. (Box-folder 1:113)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Laura Hosmer [1887] June 9, ALS with address 2 p. (Box-folder 1:114)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Laura Hosmer [1887 July 4], ALS with envelope 2 p. (Box-folder 1:115)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Laura Hosmer [1887 July 19], ALS with address 3 p. (Box-folder 1:116)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Laura Hosmer [1887 July] 25, ALS with envelope 4 p. (Box-folder 2:117)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Laura Hosmer [1887 August 8], ALS with address 2 p. (Box-folder 2:118)
  - Louisa May Alcott to Laura Hosmer [1887] December 1, ALS with envelope 4 p. (Box-folder 2:119)